- Hey.
- What's going on?
He's definitely in there.
He ain't openin' the door.
- You hopped up?
- Absolutely.
Harrold?
Harrold!
Hey, buddy, I wanna talk to you!
Open the door!
I hear him in there.
Harrold!
Take your weapons out.
Last chance, Harrold!
Fuck.
Fuckin'...
Ahh!
Shit.
Harrold! Harrold?
- Fuck! Fuck you!
- Fucking kidding me!
You fucking guys
can't kick the fuckin' door?
- Harrold, get some clothes on!
- I got my hands up.
- Don't fucking shoot me!
- Shut up! Hey!
What the fuck are you doin'?
You guys gonna just stand there?
Go in there and get him!
Put some clothes on him!
I fuckin' didn't do nothin'!
Fuck did I kick that fuckin' door?
- Hey, Commish.
- Chris.
Third floor upstairs.
- Third?
- Yeah.
- What happened with "Shan-creek-a"?
- I was just goin' over there
to have an appointment
with this female,
and this lady came out of nowhere
- and brained me with a smoothie.
- Her daughter says you pushed her.
Sir, I was tryin' to make an escape...
- Did you push her?
- After the smoothie.
- So you did...
- What's up, Tommy.
Whoa! This is an occasion.
Commish exitin' the SUV?
- Is this a homicide?
- It's not. You've been misinformed.
You're fuckin' kiddin' me.
It's not a homicide?
- Nope.
- No, sir. No, sir.
- Why are you bleeding?
- I was trying to tell your officers, sir.
This woman is crazy.
And she hit me with a fuckin'
smoothie in the head.
What are you talkin' about?
Like, a drink or somethin'?
No, like a fuckin' smoothie,
you know?
Like you would smooth
your clothes out with.
- An iron? A fuckin' iron?
- An iron!
- For fuck's sake!
- It's called an iron, Harrold.
- Yes, sir, a smoothie.
- Shut up.
Commish, I should be
a captain or a deputy-super
or probably even your job by now.
I can't take much more of this shit.
You dug that hole.
You know,
my fuckin' knee is killin' me.
He kicked the fuckin' teeth
out of a vice cop in Back Bay.
How do you fuck your knee up
kickin' a guy in the mouth?
I over-kicked.
I hyper-extended it.
- I thought he fuckin' got suspended.
- Hey! I fuckin' hear you, numb-nuts.
- Sorry, that's what I heard.
- What'd you hear?
- I heard that you got suspended.
- Do I look suspended?
- No, sir.
- He doesn't look suspended.
Would I be sittin' here starin' at you two
chowderheads if I was suspended?
No, I wouldn't.
Life is a rigged fucking game.
You two just passed "Go."
Buckle it the fuck up.
- Harrold, you're under arrest.
- Actually accurate.
You go home, put some ice
on that knee, and get some sleep.
- Got the race in five hours.
- Catchin' drunks at the marathon.
Boss, please, don't make me
wear the clown suit.
It's the last hoop, Tommy.
You walk your beat, smile,
and you're officially out of the doghouse.
One more day.
Weather's gonna be nice, pretty girls,
fresh air, be like a big picnic.
Everybody loves a picnic.
- Pizza delivery for Patrick.
- Hey, baby.
Hey.
How was work?
This sweet old man came in
and gave that to me today.
Mr. Flanagan.
His wife was on my floor
a couple months back.
Stage four, so we were just
there to keep her comfortable.
I guess before she passed,
she told him she wanted me to have it.
- Huh.
- I hardly knew them,
but he was so sweet and so sad,
and I was just holding him
and hugging him.
Look at how pretty that is.
Isn't that beautiful?
And you made me dinner?
- How's your dissertation coming?
- Huh!
- Two paragraphs, both deleted.
- Uh-huh.
And, uh, but I did tag some cool
apartments in San Francisco to show you.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
- Look at you, so excited.
- Well, I'm really excited
that we're taking
the day off tomorrow.
- Mmm.
- And I think after my masterpiece pizza,
we're gonna have to go
on a run at some point.
- Tomorrow? No, honey.
- Yeah.
There's three things
you can do on Patriots Day.
One's watch the marathon,
the other one's run the marathon,
and the third one is get down to Fenway
and yell for those Red Sox.
- Yellin' for the Red Sox.
- Sox.
- Mmm. Red "Sahx."
- Red "Sahx."
- There you go.
- I think you just wanna stay
in bed with me all day.
- Wanna know what I think?
- Mmm.
I think the reason Mrs. Flanagan
wanted you to have it
was because she knew you would
hold him when he gave it to you.
You're a very sweet man.
I know. Cheers.
To the Red Sox.
Yeah. "Sahx."
- Sox.
- "Sahx."
"Sahx."
Did you change
the software and shit?
All right, let's see.
Uh, yeah. Got it.
Yes!
- Hey, Li. What's up, guys?
- Oh, hey, Sean, what's up?
Wow!
What are you feedin' that thing?
It looks like he could
outrun the squad car.
- She definitely could.
- Look at this!
- Can I touch it?
- No.
No. No.
So what about
the Zac cowboy concert?
- Zac Brown Band, yeah.
- Yeah.
Yeah, I'll get ten tickets.
Hey, it's gonna be
a cultural experience, okay?
You're gonna get
a better education than MIT,
Harvard, BU, BC.
I need everybody's hat sizes,
we'll all get hats.
- Yeah, cool.
- Get right.
- All right, boys.
- Thanks.
Well, listen, you know
I like my chicken fried,
- a cold beer on a Friday night...
- Me, too.
...and my jeans that fit too tight.
- Just right. Your jeans, just right.
- Just right. Just right.
Do you think you'll definitely come?
- Or...
- Yes. I will be there.
Okay. Cool. Yeah.
Oh, Tommy!
I'm sorry. I just gotta
get my clothes for tomorrow.
Tommy, oh, my God.
Get the fuck out of my room.
- But this is our room.
- You know, now I can officially
tell your blood alcohol by the frequency
of key scratches on the lock.
- It's a predictive pattern, Tommy.
- I had two pops, okay?
It's medicinal.
And I got roll call...
- You sound like...
- ...in four hours and 42 minutes.
- ...elephant.
- I'm sorry. All right?
Please, come on, just go.
I'll see you in the morning.
Hey... want me
to cuddle with you?
- No! I told you to leave, Tommy.
- Come on.
- I love you.
- Go on. You're wakin' me up.
- I'm sorry. All right?
- Okay. Quit ya' talkin'.
- Go back to sleep.
- Bye-bye.
- Bye, bye.
You wanna go get your drink?
One on top?
You thirsty?
Yeah, let's go. Come on.
What do you want?
Juice? Milk?
Mommy, Mommy, open.
Here you go, baby.
Let's go in the room.
Uniform's dry.
I also swapped out the battery
in your shoulder mic.
I haven't seen you
in your uniform for a while.
Yeah, that was on purpose.
- Oh, God.
- Come on. Let me see it.
- Don't start.
- Mmm. Kinda turns me on.
- Really?
- Gotta get your hair cut first.
It's at the top of my list.
God, I gotta put this thing on.
Do I look like a clown?
- Why are you laughing?
- I'm not.
- I look like a clown.
- No! It's just...
- No, it's okay.
- It's your color.
I'm basically
a crossing guard, all right?
And they send me to the Marathon,
at the finish line
with the biggest VIPs in the city,
and everybody's gonna break my balls.
- You got my whistle and my stop sign?
- Come here. Gimme a kiss.
- I love you.
I'll see you later on, all right?
- All right.
- I'll see you tonight.
Don't kick any cops.
- I'll try not to.
- I hear they hate that.
Sweetheart?
You saw me yesterday, right?
- Mm-hmm.
- So, is it just me,
or am I gettin' a little
better lookin' every day?
Why don't you come over here, and I'll
show you how good-lookin' you are?
Boy, I wish I had time for that.
Love you.
What do you want,
a muffin or a bagel?
- Oh, bring me a muffin, please.
- Yes, doll.
- Love you!
- Hey, Tiesha.
- Morning, Sergeant Jeff.
- How's your day today?
- It is a muffin day, sweetheart.
- We got blueberry.
- Oh. You're an angel.
- I try to be, just for you.
- How's school goin'?
The boys leavin' you alone,
lettin' you study?
They are.
They have no choice.
In the cup.
- Have a great day.
- You, too.
Right over there,
next to the table.
Are we feeding
that other video or no time to?
Nobody in the VIP section at all.
Unless they have credentials, period,
all right?
Nobody.
Hey, Tommy!
- What's up?
- I got a favor.
It's actually a gift.
I'm gonna give you the finishin' line.
- Come on!
- No, no, no.
This is your welcome back, Tommy.
Means no more fuck-ups.
Just smile in front of all the VIPs
and let 'em all remember
what a great fuckin' guy
- Tommy Saunders is.
- I understand that.
- Can I just talk to you for a second?
- No, no, no, no.
Look, can't you see the beauty
of just sayin' "Thank you"?
I say, "You're welcome." Huh?
It's just a trade-off
to get your job back.
- Look...
- Nah.
No more words. I just wanna get
to the Hopkinton, all right?
- What time you gonna run?
- Under three, I hope.
That ain't happenin'.
Good luck.
What are you lookin' at?
World's most overpaid meter maid.
Wow.
You wanna move the barricades?
I gotta get to Hopkinton.
Hey! Well, don't stand around.
He told you to move the barricade, not me.
Carol!
I need you to do me a favor.
My knee's gotten swollen fatter.
I gotta have you bring the fatter
knee brace down to me, all right?
I'm at the finish line,
so you'll be able to find me.
All right, I love you, baby.
Thanks.
Yeah, but what about, like-like,
Erik and Rafi
and Brendan and those guys?
I mean, those guys were our friends,
so it's like...
Don't think about 'em.
Doesn't matter.
Bro, I'm...
Look, I'm not pussin' out or nothin'.
I'm not at all. I'm just thinkin' about
Martin Luther King, and like...
Martin Luther King
was not a Muslim.
He was a hypocrite.
He was a fornicator.
Yeah, but I'm a fornicator.
You think that's funny?
No.
Come here.
What?
- What?
- You're my brother.
- You understand that?
- Yeah.
- Are you ready for this?
Good morning, everyone.
It is great to have you with us for
the running of the Boston Marathon.
Round one starts in ten minutes.
We're looking at
a live picture of the start line
in Hopkinton where it all begins
for the runners...
Superintendent Billy Evans
representing
the Boston Police Department.
30 seconds to go. This will...
There is Lelisa Desisa,
who I think is probably the...
In remembrance of the 20 students
and six staff members
who lost their lives,
the Boston Athletic Association
wishes to express
its deepest sympathy
to the families of the victims
of all residents of Newtown.
We ask that you join us in observing
- a period of silence...
- Standby, A.
- ...of 26 seconds.
- Ready, C.
Ready C is up.
Twenty-six, 25, 24,
23, 22,
21, 20,
19, 18,
17, 16, 15,
14, 13, 12,
11, ten, nine,
eight, seven,
six, five...
...4, 3, 2, 1...
And they are off.
The elite men in the 117th running
of the Boston Marathon,
the oldest running marathon
in the United States.
You can see that the crowd
has thickened to about four deep
at some places there along
this course in Hopkinton...
Donohue,
are you on night vision?
Why are you on night vision?
That's atrocious.
And this guy owes me 20 bucks.
Watch your hand, man.
And what do I owe you $20 for again?
- 'Cause I talked to her.
- You didn't talk to her.
Get the fuck outta here.
You talked to her?
She said she's comin'
to the Zac Brown concert.
- Big mistake.
- Nice MIT girl?
She'll love it.
She'll be smitten.
Gotta take her to something
classy, like the Pops.
- The Pops?
- Yeah, the Pops.
- Name one Pop.
- Beethoven. Done.
Go to the barn!
Flank him, flank him!
♪ Pop's farm was the place to go,
load the truck up, hit the dirt road ♪
♪ Jump the barbwire,
spread the word ♪
♪ Light the bonfire,
then call the girls ♪
♪ King in the can
and the Marlboro Man ♪
♪ Jack and Jim
were a few good men ♪
♪ When we learned how to kiss
and cuss and fight, too ♪
♪ Better watch out
for the boys in blue ♪
♪ Chillin' on a dirt road ♪
♪ Laid back,
swervin' like I'm George Jones ♪
- Throw the flash bang! Throw...
- Got it!
- You do this every time!
- You're in the way of the TV!
Give me the fuckin'...
...took off so fast
that he almost caught the camera truck.
...on a course
that stretches from Hopkinton
through Ashland,
Framingham, Natick...
Desisa's to the right of your screen...
...back to the women
for a second, they got about six miles...
The elites have reached mile eight.
Expected on Boylston Street...
Paying my debt to society.
- Oh, God...
- In the doghouse, huh?
Yeah, but it's all right.
He says it's the last hoop,
so we'll see.
Get a haircut, though, will ya?
I'll cut my hair once
you stop shaving your legs.
Sorry!
Couldn't find my jacket.
Ready to go?
- Can we grab some drinks before we go?
- Sure.
- Let's get "drunch."
- You don't have to beg me.
...and as all
the contenders are in there,
and they're closing hand over fist.
Kogo, Desisa, and Gabremariam.
So Ethiopia has two of the three.
- Ready, man?
- Yes, Daddy.
- You are?
- Yeah.
- Wanna go see Mommy at the race?
- Yeah!
Wanna go cheer on Mommy
at the race?
Let's roll. Let's roll.
All right.
Yes.
...and running one of
the most famous streets in Boston...
The front-runners are approaching mile 23!
We're mere minutes away
from crowning the winner
- of the 2013 Boston Marathon.
- Get some people outta here.
This is against fire code.
We got way too many people.
- She can stay.
- Thanks, Tommy.
How are you?
How's your husband, good?
He's good.
He's doing fine.
Again, you're looking
at Heartbreak Hill now.
We're leaving the elites now.
Kenmore Square.
You see the light stanchions
over that building.
This is one of the really cool
spots in Boston...
And look at that,
the Boston Marathon running
right past Fenway Park,
which will soon empty out...
...making the right turn,
they're heading up towards Boylston.
Looks like Ethiopia
is gonna reign supreme!
And here they come!
Heading down Boylston
for the last block!
Is there anyone else on the road?
Very fast time.
Standby, camera three..
Three, two, one...
and lead the way.
Desisa is the 2013
champion of the elites.
Time to take in
what the Boston Marathon is truly about.
Watching thousands of amateur athletes
complete the amazing feat.
I'd think about losin'
that Yankees cap.
You got a lot of Sox fans in these bars.
I'd hate to see ya get tuned up.
Oh.
And say hello to Frank Night,
from Boston, Massachusetts.
Thanks.
Excuse me.
Sorry. Sorry 'bout that.
Please excuse me.
That's Police Chief
Billy Evans crossing the finish line!
Way to go, Billy!
- Thank you, Governor.
- Nice job.
Does anybody
have a big tub of melted butter?
A huge lobster
just crossed the finish line!
Hey! Leo...
- Time out.
- No time out!
- Hey!
- Baby...
- You behavin' yourself?
- Oh, yeah.
Here it is, you numbskull.
You're on your feet all day,
and you wear the wrong one?
I did it on purpose so you'd have to
bring me the fatter one.
- Romantic, right?
- I'm sure that was your plan!
- You wanna walk with me a bit?
- No, I gotta get back to work!
I gotta claw my way outta this zoo!
- I love you. Thanks for the brace.
- I love you, too.
Hey, give that to Joey.
Looking down Boylston,
you can see waves of runners
turning the corner for the final...
Did you see that guy?
There he is.
General Patton in a neon vest.
Hey, Commish, I'll get a fuckin' smoothie
and be waitin' in the back
of the Tahoe for you and Q.
Hey, grab this bozo!
Get him outta here!
Keep your eyes open, will ya?
I'm proud of ya, Tommy.
How ya feelin'?
The knee hurts.
The back hurts.
The balls hurt.
The pain sometimes feels
like it hurts
on top of the hurt,
if that's even remotely possible.
This is Davis.
No, the Biden call's
scheduled for 3:00.
Biden? Vice President Biden?
Hey, let me talk to him.
- Behave yourself, Tommy.
- Commissioner, let me talk to him!
Guys! The lobster's back!
Come here!
Cuff that lobster, will you?
Whoo!
The finalists
in the wheelchair competition here...
...very fast runners
here out on this storied course.
So much history today.
To all the runners
and our team behind the scenes,
thank you for bringing this race...
Those are bombs, Captain!
Those are bombs!
This is Delta 984!
We got multiple explosions! We need...
Shit!
All medical personnel
to the finish line! Now!
Something just exploded
at the finish line.
What did he say?
Let's turn around, Q.
I repeat, multiple casualties!
I got you.
Sir, you're gonna be okay, all right?
You're gonna be okay.
Ma'am, hold on to this
as tight as you can.
Hey, get that wheelchair
over here now!
All medical personnel
to the finish line!
- We need two over here!
- Repeat, multiple casualties!
- Tommy!
- Carol!
You okay? Huh? Lemme see.
All right. You're okay. You're okay.
Hey, Sully, come here!
Carol, go with him now!
Get her home now!
Repeat your location!
This is Delta 984!
I'm at the finish line!
I only wanna hear from the 984!
I only wanna hear
from that supervisor.
All right, this is what I need.
I want Ring Road clear,
so I can push ambulances in and out!
Keep pushin' in those ambulances!
Okay. People are coming.
Ma'am, you're on fire.
That's it.
Oh, shit!
Sir?
Can we get some help, sir?
Anyone, sir, please?
Yeah.
You're okay. You're okay.
You're okay.
We gotta take your son
and get him some help.
Leo! Leo!
You're gonna be okay, sir.
You all right? You hear me?
You're okay.
I can't...
We'll figure this out.
- I'll find you in just a minute.
- Jess...
Get the wheelchairs!
Come on!
Both of her legs
are severely lacerated.
- On three, ready?
- This is my wife.
She's gonna be okay.
Hey! Send two more ambulances
from Ring Road right now!
This is Sergeant Davis
at the Forum Cafe.
I need personnel at
the second bomb site immediately!
I need assistance!
This is Delta 984.
I'm heading to the second bomb site!
Everybody, keep this line clear!
And stop letting runners through!
Secure the perimeter!
If I see another runner,
your ass is done!
We need a fuckin'
ambulance over here!
We need ambulances down
at the second bombing site!
Starbucks and the Forum!
Are there more bombs?
No, no, no, no.
Look at me. You're gonna be okay.
- You're doin' good, all right?
- What's that? What's that?
Don't look at that!
Look at me! Look at me!
Get that over here now!
Guys, shut down the race!
Do not have another person
run down Boylston Street!
Come on, get her up, get her up!
Shut down the race!
Fuck, Tommy!
We've got two fatalities.
We got two fatalities,
and a fuckin' kid, eight years old.
- Where's his family?
- They're wounded.
They fuckin' dragged
everybody out.
- For fuck's sake, what do we do?
- I don't fuckin' know.
We gotta leave someone with him.
We cannot leave him here alone, Captain.
No, we're gonna get
someone by his side.
- I ain't goin anywhere.
- We need everybody
out of the area immediately.
We gotta clear the perimeter.
Could be more bombs.
Yeah, I'm on it.
Hey!
Anyone in here? Anyone?
Shit!
This is Delta 984.
We gotta confiscate all cell phones.
Repeat. If you see anyone recordin',
grab their phones, I don't care who it is!
They gotta find my boy.
Somebody, please...
Don't worry.
We'll find him, sir.
I don't know where he is.
Lee, I'm James. I'm going to
take care of you, all right?
You're going to be fine.
Can you feel that?
Can you wiggle your toes?
Good. Good, good, good.
We're good.
We're gonna save your leg, okay?
Hey, you gotta help me
find my son.
His name is Leo Woolfenden.
He's three years old.
We got separated somehow.
Somebody took him.
I just didn't...
You need to find him.
His name is Leo Woolfenden.
W-O-O-L...
Push out and make sure
we're keepin' people out of the perimeter.
- All right? Get moving.
- We've got a six-block perimeter set up.
We're all locked down here.
Oh, boy.
Here we go. Here we go.
- This is the first blast scene?
- Yeah.
The second was down there
at the Forum restaurant.
- Total station en route.
- Okay, we need TEDAC and OPU.
- What about cell phones, cameras?
- Yeah, we're right on top of that.
Yeah, we're collecting cell phones,
surveillance tapes,
- all the video we can find.
- Get 'em all, Tommy. Don't miss any.
How big is the secured perimeter?
Six blocks off the course
each direction.
- Let's extend that. Make it 10.
- You got it.
It's clearly coordinated.
There could be more bombs.
- How many total wounded?
- Got three fatalities that we know of.
One's a little child on the street
in front of the Forum.
What are they doin'?
What? I said that's
an eight-year-old kid under there.
No, they can't move the body.
We've gotta clear them out.
Tell them to clear out of there!
- You got it, you got it.
- Tell them to clear out of there.
- Who the fuck are you?
- Sorry, Sergeant.
Could be clues in the blood-splattered
bomb residue on the boy's body.
We can't risk moving him.
Nothing moves.
What's the matter with you guys?
You gonna tell that boy's parents
that their son's still
lyin' on the fuckin' street?
- Turn it down, Tommy.
- Oh, fuck that!
- Tommy! Let's go over there.
- All right, Billy...
Just fuckin' leave me alone,
will ya?
We've gotta decide who's running this,
and we have to decide quickly.
If it's terrorism,
it's yours, Rick.
Gentlemen, the moment we label
this terrorism, everything changes.
It's not about Boston anymore.
It's not a local investigation.
It's Wolf Blitzer.
It's stock markets.
It's politicians and knee-jerk reactions,
anti-Muslim backlash...
And what if we're wrong?
I mean, there's no take-back.
I've been through this before.
Look, your call,
but we already know it is.
And a cell is activated,
they hit Chicago or New York
or Washington,
what happens then?
The accusations are gonna come,
no matter what we do.
It's terrorism.
We'll take it.
So, what do you need?
Command center.
Really big one.
This'll do.
I want CART team over there.
Post-blast investigators
in that corner.
We need a media tent set up.
All right, let's get an evidence grid
started right over there
against that wall.
And I guarantee
these are gonna crash,
so let's get a bank of
landlines up immediately.
We're good, boss.
We'll be up in an hour.
Commissioner Davis,
the "New York Post" is reporting
a 20-year-old Saudi national
has been charged.
- Can you confirm?
- That is false.
We have not charged
anyone at this time.
We are asking the public to help us
supplement the investigation.
Anyone with photos
or video of the marathon
is encouraged to turn them in
to Boston Police.
I need you to give me access
to the following databases...
Travel, Visa...
Someone needs to get on the phone
with the United States Attorney's office.
Get us some warrants for
the cell phone towers right now.
AT&T, Verizon, T-Mobile,
all the way down the track.
Let T actical Aviation know, as of right
now, Boston owns both those planes.
Get them both to Logan.
No, I'm talkin' about the T-5's.
They're gonna be cycling from
Logan to Quantico. That's it.
FBI servers just got 12,000
e-mails in under a minute.
Holy Christ.
And we're crashed.
Get us back online now.
- Yes, sir. Yes, sir.
- Now.
28-year-old female,
Jessica Kensky.
- Pulse, 101.
- BP's 84 over 45.
Think the best
that we could do is a BKA.
The soft tissue's also compromised.
I don't think this is salvageable.
There's way
too much soft tissue damage.
We gotta take it.
There's nothin' left here.
I need some saline.
We need to wipe off this flap.
Male, late 20s with no ID.
The leg is not looking good.
All right, the vessels are controlled,
but there is no viability here.
Absolutely no blood supply.
We'll have to amputate.
Saw.
Amputating below the knee, left leg.
We're recreating the scene.
Put every item down
exactly where it was found.
We need this spread out here.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Lay some paper down.
Let the stuff air dry.
I don't want to degrade the DNA.
Carol? Pick up the phone!
Carol, can you hear me?
Get this paper over here.
If you come across any clothing
that's burnt or charred, separate that.
I need to have somebody collect these
cell phones here, get 'em down to CART.
Okay, people, remember,
- the bombs had to be carried in somehow.
- Carol, you gotta call me back
as soon as you get
this message, all right?
...on large bags and/or backpacks.
Sort these out by adapter types.
Anything with a camera, we need
to get over to the import station.
Are those GPS tags
comin' through okay?
Yes, sir.
All right.
Yeah, I got him right here.
JFK Library's not an explosion.
Hello? Oh, Carol!
I've been calling and calling!
Tommy, Jesus.
Are you okay?
Yeah, yeah, I'm fine.
You're not hurt, are ya?
I'm fine, Tommy.
My mother's here.
- Everybody's here.
- Oh, thank God!
The news is going crazy.
They're sayin'
there could be more bombs.
- Please be careful, Tommy.
- I will. I gotta go, all right?
I'm gonna call you
as soon as I can.
I love you.
Hey, Sarge, heard you on the radio
this afternoon. Hell of a job.
I thought I heard your
squeaky-ass voice in my ear.
Don't fuck around right now,
Mike, please?
I'm not fuckin' around.
You did good.
Hey, honey, it's me.
Sweetheart,
I've got out one day too late.
I will. No.
I love you, too.
What are those guys doin' here?
They weren't even down there!
What the fuck is this, a joke?
They're the FBI and they're in charge,
Tommy, so just do as you're told.
And their boss,
I wouldn't wanna be that guy.
He's triple-fucked.
One, he steps up and takes it.
- Two, now he's gotta solve the thing.
- What's three?
He's gotta walk around
inside that life all day long.
- Fuckin' shoot me four times and...
- Button it up, Tommy.
These young guys
are lookin' up to you.
I don't need the ass-ache
from you today.
- Just do as you're fuckin' told!
- Fine.
We have no evidence
this was a suicide attack.
So these IED's were most likely
remotely detonated.
It is highly probable
these bombs were homemade.
It is likely that they made more.
What does Mass State think?
I think we need to get air assets
from the National Guard.
I think we need a couple
additional tactical teams.
But most importantly,
there's two bathrooms
in this place,
and one's broken.
Right, I'll get on to that.
It is safe to say that we're dealing
with more than one individual,
- some degree of sophistication.
- Excuse me, Agent Deh-law-ray?
- Special Agent DesLauriers.
- Sorry about that.
- Look, I just wanted to say...
- It's not the time or place.
I just want to say,
I work Homicide.
I know one thing closes cases...
witnesses.
So we oughta get our asses
to the hospital, interview the victims.
Could be someone
saw somethin', no?
Tommy, get some of
our guys on this.
And keep in mind that the bomber
could be among the wounded.
We've seen it before.
So let's get positive lD's on everybody
comin' into the hospital.
Let's show this cocksucker
he messed with the wrong fuckin' city.
We're getting
conflicting reports about the arrest
of a Saudi national earlier.
Now, Commissioner Davis
at this time is insisting
that no suspects
have been arrested.
Dzhokhar! I asked you
to get whole milk. This is two percent.
It's milk. She's a baby.
She can't taste the difference.
No, she can't,
but I will when she gets sick.
Feed the baby in the bedroom.
I can't hear the news.
What am I supposed to give her?
- This isn't gonna work.
- Feed the baby in the bedroom.
- I can't hear...
- I needed whole milk!
I'll take care of it! Feed her
in the bedroom right now! Go!
Make him get whole milk.
We shouldn't have put
the bombs ground level.
We shoulda
put that shit waist-high.
- Go get the right milk, Dzhokhar. Go!
- What? No.
I don't wanna hear any more of
her bullshit. Go get the right milk.
Mind if I ask you
a couple of questions?
Did you see anything
out of the ordinary?
- Anything suspicious?
- Nah.
Did you see anybody
put bags down or...
Thank you very much.
Appreciate it.
Has anybody spoken
to you guys yet?
No? What's your name, sweetie?
My knee's killing me.
You got some Tylenol back there?
We got all kinds of stuff, Sergeant.
You want a Vicodin?
- No, no Vicodin. Tylenol.
- Tylenol, Tylenol.
- Make it four pills, please.
- Okay, you got it.
Thank you.
Hey, do we have a name on him yet?
No, the EMT said he was
with his wife at the site.
But all I've got is this ring.
It's engraved
"PB and J. 8-25-12."
- She's gotta be in a different hospital.
- Let me call around.
They are still keeping people
out of this area, obviously.
Still that 15-block area
that was mentioned earlier.
- Here you go.
- Thank you.
- It's fried rice? Eggroll?
- Yeah. Everything's in there.
Okay.
It's a very scary day today.
My name is Danny.
What was your name?
My name's Kara.
- Nice to meet you.
- Nice to meet you, too.
- Are you from Boston?
- Yeah, I live here.
Oh, I live in Cambridge.
- Oh, that's not far.
- No.
The FBI
has taken over the criminal investigation
into the bombings.
The Bureau is asking you
for any visual...
- Hey, John.
- Hey, what's up?
- This fucking bombing, huh?
- Awful.
- Are we gonna supplement this?
- Not that I know of.
It's all BPD.
- What do you got?
- Everything's busted.
The radio bracket's loose.
The right window goes down
when I put on the blinker.
Tell me this thing
about the blinker?
Yeah, it goes down,
but only when I signal right.
'Course, the big question this morning...
- Who did this?
- That is fuckin' weird.
And why did they do this?
Excuse me. Sir?
Sorry to disturb you.
- Is this Jessica Kensky?
- Yes. She's my daughter.
Hey, I understand.
- I can come back, okay?
- No, that's... Sorry.
How can we help you?
I just wanna know
if she said anything at all?
- If she communicated anything?
- Not much.
She just asked
about her husband.
We don't know where he is.
His name is Patrick Downes.
- Can you help us find him?
- You leave that to us, okay?
- Okay?
- Thank you.
My God. Oh...
- Hey.
- What are you guys doin' here?
What the fuck happened out there?
What's goin' on?
Is this fuckin' Al-Qaeda or what?
Was it Al-Qaeda?
Are you fuckin' eating
Cheerios on my couch?
- Hey, Tommy...
- Who did it? What are they sayin'?
What happened?
Listen, was it Al-Qaeda or what?
We're gonna give him
some space, all right?
Does someone wanna tell us
what the hell happened?
Get everybody outta here. Get the...
get the fuck outta here now!
- Every fuckin' one of you!
- Come on! What the hell did I do?
What do you mean?
Fuckin' come on!
- Sorry!
- Get the fuck outta here!
Whatever you want, Tommy.
Whatever you need, whatever you need.
Blue coat.
I've got a street-block radius.
Yeah, it's a little grainy.
Time doesn't match it.
You got 'em?
I don't... I don't know.
It's okay, baby.
I don't even understand what I saw.
I keep seein' this blood.
It's, like, everywhere.
I saw a foot next to...
This boy from...
Well, I think from Marathon Sport.
He looked like a little BU kid.
Like a good kid, Carol, you know?
He had an assistant manager tag
and, um...
he helped, we moved her.
We... we laid her down.
Blood just started to spread,
his knee was in her blood...
And then there was
an eight-year-old boy.
He was just layin' there.
They had to take his family away,
and his parents, and fuck, he's fuckin'...
I got these images in my head.
They ain't goin' away.
And you were right there.
Please don't be mad at me
that I told you to come down there.
I shouldn't have told you
to come down there.
You never could have known.
Baby, it's not your fault.
I'm sorry, Carol.
I'm sorry that I told you to come.
I'm sorry that I put you there.
We gotta find
these motherfuckers, Carol.
We gotta get out there
and find these motherfuckers
before they do this
to somebody else.
Back it up three seconds.
Boss!
This guy. White hat.
Play it again.
He's the only one that looks away.
Feds wanna talk to you.
Rick. Sergeant Saunders.
Thank you for coming so quickly.
Whatever it is, I didn't do it.
Ed tells me you're familiar
with this area?
Yeah, why?
- Let's run it.
- White Hat.
Play it back.
The guy right there
with the white hat?
- That's the guy, isn't it?
- We believe so.
It's gotta be.
Okay, so I am White Hat.
At exactly 2:45,
I am seen by the surveillance videos
outside the Forum restaurant, okay?
Now, Sergeant, as you can see, we've
recreated the Boylston Street crime scene.
Now, let's move left of boom.
Left of what?
Left of boom.
Left of the explosions.
We need to trace him backwards.
You know this street, right?
And you know which places
have security cameras?
Yeah, yeah.
I know what you're doin'.
That's the finish line there.
You said 2:45?
Correct.
All right, so where is he at 2:44?
Who can see him?
- It's gotta be Crate & Barrel.
- Crate & Barrel, anybody?
Checking Crate & Barrel.
Yes, sir!
I see you. 2:44 p.m.
The hat's got a golf logo along
with the number three.
Okay. I wanna find every store
in Boston that's selling that hat.
Pull the names from
the credit card receipts...
Crate & Barrel.
...then cross-check it
against facial recognitions.
Okay, Sergeant.
I'm Crate & Barrel at 2:44.
Who sees me now?
It's the Walgreen's
that's across the street now.
- Abe 'n Louie's?
- Abe 'n Louie?
Checking Abe 'n Louie's.
- Anybody got Abe 'n Louie?
- Nothing, sir.
- No?
- No, sir.
Come on, Sergeant.
Where else?
Gimme a minute, all right?
Lemme think. Um...
Across the street, the Mandarin...
The Mandarin?
Nah, their cameras
face the wrong direction.
Remember, that kid
stole a purse from Solas?
He ran into Peet's.
Ah, I got it...
Um, Back Bay Social Club!
Teddy put in new
patio cameras last year.
Back Bay Social Club.
Searching Back Bay Social Club.
I got him!
Back Bay Social Club.
2:40 p.m.
I have a new angle on his face.
His left eye, the chin.
It's still not clear enough
for facial recognitions.
All right, push that out to CART team,
see if they can fill in the blanks.
Doin' great, Sergeant.
Keep going.
All right. 2:42 p.m.
Whiskey's Steak House.
- Whiskey's Steak House!
Got him. 2:37.
White Hat's standing with someone.
It's a man wearing aviators.
Looks like they know each other.
Motherfucker!
You fuckin' piece 'a shit!
Two bombers.
- Give me a kiss.
- No!
- Then get out.
- Stop it.
Get out.
There you go. You gotta put
the bunny, like, right there.
No.
- Yes. What?
- No.
What do you mean, no?
...still a very heavy police presence.
The FBI reportedly zeroing in
on a possible suspect.
They figured that out
quicker than you thought, huh?
And amid all the questions
about a possible suspect today...
Come on. I'll help you.
Your baby doesn't
know how to tie her shoes.
I've got it.
- Jahar?
- Nah, I don't want any.
...caused chaos in the markets today.
It also, we understand, forced the FBI
to cancel what was
a scheduled news conference.
It has never been
rescheduled since.
How can we have zero hits
on facial recognition?
Well, the technology isn't perfect,
Governor, we've got partial images.
We've got bad angles.
These are pretty clear
fucking pictures.
One of the suspects
is wearing sunglasses.
- Run it through the NSA's system.
- We're using the NSA's system, sir.
We need to get these
photos out to the public.
Not yet. We have a couple of
decent leads, but right now...
We release these photos,
the city eats these guys.
No, I agree.
So why don't you
get over there and say somethin'?
Look, this is Ed's fuckin' deal
right now, all right?
These guys are somebody's friends,
neighbors, co-workers.
- You got no balls.
- I've got fucking plenty of balls.
I'm not gettin' involved
with the Governor.
I'll go over there
and say somethin'.
You wanna get yourself
suspended again?
If we release those photos now,
it tells the suspects
that we don't know who they are,
- and that puts them ahead of us...
- That's true, but...
But what?
But what if we're wrong?
What if these men are innocent?
And God forbid,
they also happen to be Muslims,
we will be crucified!
They don't look like
prototypical jihadists to me.
What does a prototypical
jihadist look like, Rick?
You got a photo of one?
Okay, listen, that all sounds
very by-the-book, Rick,
okay, but we owe people answers.
We can't just sit back
and keep analyzing data.
What does your gut tell you?
My gut tells me that
these are probably our guys.
But I'm not ready
to release the photos.
Gotta give our people
some more time to work.
Okay. Okay, it's decided.
We'll wait.
At this time,
there have been no new developments
regarding the Boston
Marathon bombings...
We wish we had better information
as far as them being able to
find somebody right now.
It just seems like
it's an ongoing active search...
It was a beautiful day to be in Boston.
And then, in an instant,
the day's beauty was shattered.
For millions of us,
what happened on Monday is personal.
It's personal.
So we come together
to pray and mourn.
But we also
come together today
to reaffirm that the spirit
of this city is undaunted.
And the spirit of this country
shall remain undimmed.
That's the spirit
you've displayed in recent days.
- Hey. Hey, Li.
- Hey.
- Hey, Sean.
- Oh, hey...
I like those glasses.
Those are new, huh?
Yeah, thanks.
We needed a study break,
so I thought you might like one, too.
Thanks, Li, yeah.
Coffee Coolattas.
These are great.
Uh, well, we should go back to work.
But, um, Saturday night,
Zac Brown Band?
Yeah, that's right.
Are you guys...
I'll make sure all you guys
are covered, so you're in.
It's just gonna be us.
Is that cool?
- Yeah?
- That's better. Yeah.
- No, I prefer that, yeah.
- Cool. Bye.
- All right.
Good seein' you guys.
All right, let's pipe it down
so I can make this quick, please.
Situation in Boston remains in flux.
Let's be prepared to augment
should they require our assistance.
Uh, speed limit
on Common Street
has now officially been
down to 25 for a month.
So, warning period is over.
Quit giving warnings there
a week ago, Sarge.
I gave Mimi O'Brien a citation
for speeding
and expired registration.
Well, you're a braver man
than I am, Gunga Din.
We got an information vacuum.
Those are not our guys.
Meanwhile, you guys
aren't any closer
to identifying the two
we're really lookin' for.
We need to release
those pictures.
If we release the photos now,
we have zero control.
If we overplay our hand,
we may force these guys to react.
Gentlemen, if I may?
Right now,
Boston's workin' against us.
As normal, you've got a murder,
no one rats.
We don't got that problem,
'cause in this city,
when it comes to terrorism,
everybody wants to talk.
Look, you got a lot of people talkin', but
they're talkin' about the wrong people.
You release the photos of our guys,
sit back and listen. Trust me.
You gotta start lettin' Boston
work for us, I'm telling you.
I understand Boston,
but I can't just snap my fingers.
This decision goes all the way up
to the Attorney General.
Then give me his number.
I'll call him right now!
This is my fuckin' city, Rick!
Release the goddamn pictures!
Say again?
Hold on, stay on the line.
Don't lecture me on intelligence,
okay, Ed? That is what I do!
- Sir?
- What?
White Hat, Black Hat.
Fox got the pictures.
They want what we have,
or they're gonna release them.
Repeat that. Say that again.
Fox is gonna release the pictures
in 20 minutes, sir.
With or without a consult.
Okay, I'm all about
inter-agency cooperation,
but when this is over,
I am gonna hunt down the piece of shit
that leaked those photos,
and I will fucking ruin him!
I'm not gonna let Fox News
run this investigation.
We will release the pictures
as soon as the president is wheels up.
We initially developed
one person of interest,
not knowing if that individual was working
alone or in concert with others.
The FBI has developed
a second suspect.
Today, we are enlisting
the public's help
in identifying these two suspects...
Officials say
they've made the images public now
because they need help
in connecting the faces
of the potential suspects...
...the other walking
just a short distance behind.
They believe that
someone out there would recognize
at least one,
perhaps both of these men,
and call in some vital information
to law enforcement.
If you have any information at all,
please reach out to the FBI.
Investigators tonight
are working to identify a young white man
spotted in surveillance video
from the Lord & Taylor.
He was in the crowd
right before the second explosion.
He was carrying a backpack,
talking on his cell phone,
wearing a black jacket,
gray hoodie,
and a white baseball cap
on backwards.
No one should
attempt to apprehend him
except law enforcement.
Let me reiterate that caution.
Do not take any action on your own.
...identifying these two suspects.
Somebody out there knows
these individuals as friends.
Federal law
enforcement authorities now believe
that a team of at least two men
carried out the bombings here.
Not a lone wolf,
but two men described tonight
as armed and extremely dangerous.
We initially developed one person...
They are now
the world's most wanted men.
Two men in their 20s caught on tape.
Suspect number one...
- Who are you texting?
- No one.
Get everything packed in the car.
It's time to leave.
All right.
Can I have my gun now, though?
I just like...
I really want the gun now.
Dzhokhar,
you will get your gun!
- When?
- Enough!
The pictures are blurry.
They're no good.
No, the pictures are good.
Pictures are really good.
- Hey, man, where's Jahar at?
- I don't know.
Did you guys see
the press conference?
One of the guys looks
exactly fuckin' like him.
- Yo, that's what I fuckin' said.
- No way. Everybody's fuckin' paranoid.
- He looks exactly fuckin' like him.
- He texted me.
He said to get some of his stuff.
Go ahead, Dias.
I got a study group to get to.
- Don't steal my shit!
- Fuck you, man.
Fuck you!
Don't touch my shit.
- Study group, dickhead.
- Fuckin' asshole.
Gnarly, man, you can't drive
that thing on the beach.
You're gonna get arrested again!
Relax, Bob.
You can't get arrested...
This joint is kicked.
It's all done.
It's cashed out.
Where does Dzhokhar
keep his weed at?
Of course.
The coveted closet.
Yep, yep, yep, yep.
Shit.
There's no weed in here.
What's that shit?
Don't fuckin' know.
Is that fuckin' fireworks?
What the fuck does he need
fireworks for?
- Hey, these are fuckin' BB's, man.
- What are you saying?
What are you fucking
talking about, man?
This is fuckin' bomb shit.
Are you guys really that fuckin' high
you can't see this shit?
- What the fuck do we do?
- I don't know, man. You found it.
Seriously? We found it.
Quiet the fuck down
and put the stuff in the bag.
We can't leave it here.
Bag it up, man!
What the fuck you think
I'm doin', man?
We're still waiting
to hear more about suspects.
With pictures
being available to the public,
the FBI has yet to receive any...
We now await
one key lead, the names of these men.
- Is it hot? Yeah.
- It's fucking hot.
- So you broke a finger cheerleading?
- Yeah.
I did a backflip and came down
on my hand like that.
Were you before, like, people throw you
up really high, and then you come...
Yeah, I fell.
I got a concussion my senior year.
And I tried to get up and I tried to walk,
and my entire left body was numb.
Like, I couldn't walk.
I feel like I'd be really
lonely if I was here.
- Like, you're alone, right?
- Yeah, it's okay.
In the beginning,
like three years ago, it was harder.
Now, it's like, you make new friends
and you find new people.
You wanted a gun.
Now you need a gun.
Unless you know someone
that has one.
242, what's your status?
I'm in the Quad, tucked next to
the Koch building for the next 45.
Got my eyes
on Main Street and Vasser.
After that,
I got dinner break for 30.
Can I do it?
Denver 544. Koch is quiet.
We're gonna rotate you
over to Kresge.
Yeah, it is very dry out here.
So if you want me to rotate,
I'm absolutely ready.
Copy that.
Grab the gun, Dzhokhar!
No, no! No, no, no!
- Come on!
- He won't fucking let go!
Fuck you!
- Why won't you let go?
- Watch out!
No!
- Let's go!
- What now, motherfucker?
Hey!
Come on,
you fuckin' piece of shit!
Let's go! Come on!
All units. All units.
This is a Commonwealth-wide
all-points bulletin.
We have a report
of an officer shot at MIT.
Requesting available units
for search for suspects.
Witnesses report
two men fleeing the scene.
Caucasian, medium build,
dark clothing.
Suspects are armed.
Use caution.
A team, we have no suspect
information at this time.
Nothing.
Sorry to bother, uh,
can you help me real quick?
Sorry.
Yeah, I just want you to...
- Hey, don't...
- Do not move.
Do not fucking move.
What is your name?
Manny.
Yeah? Do you know about
the Marathon bombing, Manny?
Yes, I know.
- Do you know who did it?
- No.
I did that.
You understand?
And I just killed a police officer.
Bet you got a lot of money.
Give me your wallet.
Let's go.
Yeah, yeah...
Just take everything.
Just take it.
Take everything.
Your name is not Manny.
No, it's...
My name's Dun Meng.
It a-sound... it a-sound like Manny.
It sounds like Manny.
If you lie to me again,
wallahi, I will kill you.
I'm sorry.
- Open the back!
- Do not fucking move.
Open the back!
- Open the back.
- Okay, okay.
Easy, buddy. Go ahead.
Good. Give me the keys.
- Stay in the car.
- Okay.
I'll get the pressure cookers.
- Is that it?
- That's it. Get in the car.
Shit.
That's all right.
Easy, easy.
You can just take the car.
It's all right. It's all right.
It's all right.
Follow me.
All right. Let's go.
Do not say anything.
Stay quiet.
Look at me. Look at me.
Look at me.
Get in the car.
You understand?
- You're gonna get in the car...
- Yes, yes.
- ...and you're gonna be quiet.
- Yes.
All right? Let's go.
Get in the car.
Get in the car right now.
- Jahar?
- Yeah?
- Watch him.
- All right.
- Yo, does this have an iPod plug-in?
- Huh?
- Does your car have an iPod plug-in?
- No. No.
You're sure? What about Bluetooth?
You got Bluetooth?
I can plug my phone in
and play some stuff?
Sorry, there's no Bluetooth.
Do you have anyone
that cares about you?
Nobody care about me here.
Then put on the seatbelt.
No one gets through,
you hear me?
We need oxygen now.
I don't know, Travis, it's bad.
Yeah, it's Sean. I...
They tried to take his gun,
but he wouldn't give it up.
They shot him. They...
No pulse. He's gone.
Dookie, take it easy.
Stay under the limit.
Damn. This thing moves.
Really?
Yo, can I drive it?
- You wanna drive it?
- Yeah.
- No way.
- Why?
Bro, I've never driven a Benz.
I really wanna drive a Benz.
Jahar, you're not going to
drive this car.
Get over it.
You're going the wrong way, Officer.
Hey! Turn around! Hey, you!
Where are you headin'? Home?
- We're goin' to his mother's house.
- All right, get off the street.
The Boston Marathon
tragedy is being described
as the worst act of domestic terrorism
since the September 11 th attacks.
However, unlike the attacks
on the World Trade Center...
Fuck them!
You know that's bullshit,
right, Manny?
- Yes.
- 9/11...
Uh...
Muslims didn't
blow up those buildings.
- The U.S. government did.
- Yes, I know.
- You know?
- I know.
Are you saying yes
because you believe it,
or are you saying yes because
you don't want us to kill you?
Sorry, I don't know who did it.
9/11...
Yo, you need to educate yourself, dog.
For real, that's the problem
with this country.
No one knows what goes down.
America is fake as fuck.
The government did all that shit.
The government.
To make Americans
hate real Muslims.
A lot of people who say
they were at 9/11, they're all actors.
- I didn't know that.
- Well, now you know.
Of course you didn't.
You're conditioned by the media.
Yeah.
Take your ATM card.
Give it to Jahar.
What is your PIN number?
Your PIN number!
I need your PIN number.
- What is your PIN number?
- 6-2-2-8.
- Did you get that?
- What?
- 6...
- 6-2-2-8.
6-2-2-8. Okay.
Okay, Jahar, get as much
money as you can, okay?
- Well, I look wack as fuck.
- Jahar!
- Get as much money as you can.
- All right.
Times Square is...
42nd Street and Broadway...
Boom!
Time to New York, 3 hours, 42 minutes.
Please, can I just leave
and you can take the car?
- You want to leave?
- You can just...
You want to leave the car?
Are you asking me to leave the car?
- Fuck that.
- No, no, no.
I leave the car, you take the car.
No, you're not going anywhere.
You're gonna stay right there.
I won't...
I won't call the police.
Please, I have a family in China.
I have a mama,
I have a daddy.
I have a brother.
I have...
Please?
I don't call anyone.
Just let me go.
Shut the fuck up.
Fill up the tank.
The pump's busted.
It's cash only.
- Get something to eat, too.
- All right. Want somethin' to eat?
No.
- You're not hungry?
- No, that's okay.
I'll get him something.
Gonna be a long ride.
- Fuck you!
- Fuck!
What the fuck happened?
Call the police!
Call police, please!
- What happened?
- Please call!
Two people,
they kidnapped me.
They said they're
the Marathon bombers...
Call the police!
9-1-1 recorded line.
What's the nature of your emergency?
I am in Mobil gas station.
I have one claiming
someone wants to shoot him.
And he stay inside,
and he won't leave.
Can I speak with him?
Hello? Please help me!
Please help me!
Two people, they came to my car,
and they have guns.
All units, possible carjacking.
At least two males,
white, mid-twenties
at the Mobil station
off Memorial and River Street.
Witness is an Asian male,
name unclear.
Emergency operator had trouble
understanding him.
Requesting units to investigate.
Patrol Unit 488 responding.
I don't understand.
Why are we doing this?
Why do I have to take this car?
This car's so much better!
Because they're gonna
be looking for us now in this one.
No, but then why don't
we just get another car?
We'll just get, like, a better car.
- We can jack a Lambo...
- Get the fucking bombs.
- ...or something actually working.
- Get the fucking bombs, all right?
Just listen to me for a second!
If we get another car,
like, an actual car...
Listen to me, Tamerlan, please!
Listen to me!
Stop treating me like a fucking baby!
You fucking distracted me!
You distracted me.
That's why he got away.
Do you understand that?
What? This is not my fault!
Are you fucking kidding me?
This is your fault!
You were up front with him!
I was in the back the whole time, and I
went to get snacks, you piece of shit.
Don't fucking accuse me!
Fucking be quiet right now.
Do you understand?
- Dzhokhar...
- Okay. Okay.
- You be fucking quiet right now.
- All right, all right.
- Or I'll fucking kill you myself!
- Do you understand me, Jahar?
- Yeah. Yeah.
I'll fucking shoot you myself!
- All right. Yeah.
- Do you understand me?
You distracted me.
That's how he got away.
You're gonna do as I say and grab the
fucking bombs and put them in the trunk.
- All right.
- And do as I fucking say, you understand?
- Yeah.
- Right now.
You fucking get in the car!
I'll find somewhere
to ditch the Mercedes.
And you will follow me.
- Got it?
- Yeah.
- Hey, Phil, what's up?
- He's over here, Sarge.
- Hey. What's goin' on?
- I can't get a word out of him.
Let me talk to him for a second.
Sir, how are you? You okay?
Two people, they take my car.
They take my car over there in the...
They drive me around for, like,
an hour, and they say they put a...
- Wait, what did you say?
- These people, they tell me
they gonna do the explosion
in New York.
What?
They're the Marathon race bombers.
Wait, no, no, calm down.
Just calm down for a second.
Did you just say
"Marathon bombers"?
They said to you that they were
the Marathon bombers?
Yes, they told me.
They are the Marathon bombers!
Listen to me.
What kind of car do you drive?
It's my black Mercedes SUV.
That car has a GPS.
The tracking number
is 3422347.
- Well, how do you know that number?
- I just remember.
Please, they're very dangerous.
You have to catch them.
You know what? It took a lot of balls
to escape like you did.
Hey, you're a very brave guy.
Do you hear me?
Go catch those motherfuckers!
Fuck! Fuck!
Wasn't my fucking fault!
Look, you fucking fuck!
All units,
be on alert for a black Mercedes SUV,
possible carjacking suspect.
GPS shows the vehicle in Watertown,
south of Mount Auburn Street.
Baker 364 responding.
All right, Chris,
maybe stay awake tonight, you know?
Just for a change of pace.
Sarge, it's Joey.
Think I got eyes on
that Mercedes called in earlier.
I'm gonna flip around
and follow him.
He stopped.
He's on Laurel off Dexter.
Hold up, Reynolds.
I'm comin' in behind you.
Light 'em up whenever you're ready.
Fuck! Fuck! Fuck! Fuck! Fuck!
Fuckin' shit!
Jesus fuckin' Christ!
Shots fired! Shots fired!
I need units down here!
61 Laurel Street!
- Jesus Christ! Joey, you all right, man?
- Yeah, I'm all right!
Drop your weapon
and come out...
Jesus!
Give it up!
You got nowhere to go! Fuck!
All units, we have shots fired
at the vehicle in question from Cambridge.
Last seen near Dexter Ave.
We need units
to assist in Watertown.
- Can I use the gun?
- No, no, grab the bomb.
- Let me use it.
- Grab the bomb. Get it.
Joey, use the car for cover!
Light it! Light! Light, light, light!
Ahh! God!
Oh, Jesus!
God fucking damn it!
- Fuck! Joey!
- Fuckin', Sarge, where are ya?
Follow me! Follow my voice!
Jesus! Dispatch,
I need backup down here!
They've got explosives.
Shots fired! Shots fired!
Shit! Jammed.
Fuckin' come on!
Who the fuck are these guys?
Watertown P.D.
reporting shots fired
from black Mercedes
matching APB.
Delta 984 responding.
Oh, shit! Fuck!
- Sarge, what's goin' on? Sarge!
- Get the fuck in the basement!
We can take 'em.
How many clips you got?
- This is my last one.
- Shit!
Fuck you!
Doing good.
You're doing very good.
You okay?
Fuck! I'm goin' for
my machine gun! Stay here.
You cocksuckin'
piece of fuckin' shit!
What the fuck?!
Sarge, I got a mini-sledge!
Give 'em hell, brother!
Whoa! Miguel!
Miguel, it's me, Joey!
Holy shit, dude!
Are you all right?
I'm all right.
Push onto Laurel.
And cover my ass.
I'll get behind you.
- Let's go!
- Go slow.
Okay, go, go!
It won't light.
- Come on, come on...
- Come on, you fucking...
- Come on, come on!
- Fuck!
Jesus! Fuck!
Fuck!
Welcome to Watertown,
motherfucker!
Fuck you, bitch!
Christ!
Miguel, you all right?
Fuck you!
Shit!
Joey!
Joey, get the gun!
Get the gun!
Fuck! Joey!
Fuck!
Fall back!
Fall back! Go, go, go!
Come on!
Let's get to the car!
Go! Get behind me!
Get behind me!
Come on, come on!
They got fuckin' bombs, Sarge!
They're shooting at us!
Yeah, no shit.
I'm gonna flank 'em.
Joey!
We got units comin' in!
This is it, Jahar.
This is it.
- My fucking leg!
- You okay? Are you okay?
You should prepare. Now.
Want some more, motherfuckers?
You want some more?
- The fuck?
- Jesus!
Donohue! On my six!
Take the car to New York.
You finish it!
We're killing them all.
We're killing them all!
Go fuck 'em up.
Loud explosions!
Loud explosions! Loud explosions!
Fuck.
Dookie, go!
Take him out!
Officer down!
We need an ambulance!
Get an ambulance now!
Put your hands on there!
Hold on, Donohue.
Get him out of here!
Hang in there! Hang in there!
Get an ambulance!
We need help! Officer down!
Go, go, go!
This is Delta 984 in pursuit
of a black Mercedes SUV
headin' east on Laurel Street!
Stop the vehicle!
What the...
Fuck!
- Get the fuck on the ground!
- What the fuck's the matter with you?
BPD, you fuckin' morons!
We heard black truck!
I'm fuckin' sorry! You all right?
- That's him right there! Come on!
- All right, let's go! Move out!
77-16 to Control.
Need an ambulance
on Laurel Avenue.
Suspect in custody.
Shot and run over.
Repeat. Shot and run over.
I gotta fucking quit smoking.
He's gone.
- Paddles.
- Charge to 200, please.
- Nothing. No pulse.
- Charging to 200.
- All clear.
- Clear.
- Anything in response?
- No.
Raise the charge to 200.
- Charging.
- Clear?
- Clear.
- Internal paddles.
Let's have a direct shock to the heart.
Chest compression, please,
while we do this.
I need you to step back right now.
This has to happen now.
- Get outta here!
- Excuse me, step back.
I'm with the FBI. This has to happen
right now. Just stand back.
Good Lord.
Give me some more sponges.
I gotta stop the bleeding in here.
- He's in.
- Bag him.
- Get the paddles ready.
- Nothing. No pulse.
- All clear.
- Clear!
- Anything?
- Nothing.
Okay, I'm calling it.
1:35 a.m. Mark it.
Tamerlan Tsarnaev.
Lived in Cambridge with his wife
Katherine and his
younger brother Dzhokhar.
Get HRT, S.O.G., bomb techs over there
right now and shut it down.
Give me a hard perimeter.
Evacuate a block.
- Make it two blocks.
- Got it.
- We have a problem.
- What's up?
- Black Hat, Tamerlan Tsarnaev?
- Yes.
- We might have known this guy.
- Known him how?
He popped up
on a Guardian watch list.
All right, get me the list.
Right fucking here!
During the pursuit, one of the suspects
was critically injured,
transported to hospital,
where he was pronounced dead.
Now, here's where we stand.
Extensive manhunt in Watertown...
Report that an Asian male
who came in contact with the suspects
told police that the brothers discussed
New York City as their next destination.
You heard?
We got positive ID on Black Hat.
Yes, Tsarnaev.
We heard. Black Hat.
What about White Hat?
How sure are we that
he's still within the perimeter?
It's hard to be sure
in the dark like this.
My guys are runnin' on fumes.
- Two sheds.
- We're tracking reports.
A taxi picked up a guy
matching White Hat's description
from Watertown to South Station.
Could be he's on his way
to New York.
Okay.
Warn Governor
Cuomo and Mayor Bloomberg.
As for Boston, I'm calling it.
We're shutting down the city
until further notice.
Inform all transit systems
and let's get a PBA out immediately.
All civilians are asked
to please shelter in place.
Every inch of this city
is getting searched.
You positive
you wanna do this, Governor?
That's close to martial law.
T ell your people to be judicious
with the door kicking.
We got laws.
People still have rights.
This murderer is
not causing any more harm to this city.
We're shuttin' it down.
State Control
with an important announcement.
Due to the ongoing manhunt
for a person wanted...
Police in your area
are conducting an ongoing manhunt
for a person wanted in connection
with Monday's Marathon bombing.
All businesses in these towns
remain closed until further notice.
Residents in Watertown, Newton,
Waltham, Belmont,
Cambridge are advised...
...are advised to stay indoors.
Residents should remain
and not answer the door
unless it is a police officer.
Residents are advised
to stay away from windows.
Close your windows.
Go back inside your houses.
Don't answer the door.
Boston Police,
open the door, please.
You got anybody
in the house with you?
No, it's okay. It's cool.
You're supposed to be
stayin' inside.
So get a little air
and then head back, all right?
- Will do.
- All right, pal.
- Thanks.
- Thank you.
All right, let's move.
Per FBI command,
anyone making contact
with suspect's wife
Katherine Russell
is instructed to detain
in place and advise.
Do not Mirandize.
Do not interview.
- He just said no Miranda.
- Yeah, I know.
- I mean, I never hear of that. You?
- No. Never.
- Who would call that?
- I don't know. AG? CIA?
Fuckin' President.
How do I know?
Basically he's got
home videos, boxing, wrestling.
Stuff we see all the time.
And porn.
A lot of fucking porn.
This guy watched more porn
than Bin Laden.
Okay, Washington is flying up
a team to interview the wife.
Let's get her picked up
immediately.
Sir, we just got a hit
on White Hat's phone.
- Whereabouts?
- U Mass Dartmouth.
- Let's get HRT to U Mass Dartmouth.
- They're on their way, sir.
Dickhead.
You're missing class
for an ass-whuppin'.
- Wide open, man.
- I'm just letting you know.
I don't wanna go
to Crystal's stupid party.
- Go, go, go!
- Shit!
Get down! Get down! Get down!
Let me see your face!
Don't move! Don't move!
Look at me.
Victor 1-1 to Talk.
We do not have White Hat.
Room is clear
for EOD and Forensics.
Repeat, we do not have White Hat.
No. Negative. Right.
We're gettin' tips from kids sayin'
they buy their pot from White Hat.
Apparently,
he's the biggest dealer at U Mass.
Commish, they just called
from Black Falcon.
They got the wife.
Not what you were
expecting, huh, Commish?
It never is.
S.A.C. DesLauriers?
- I'm looking for S.A.C. DesLauriers.
- Rick DesLauriers.
Hi, I'm Mike Thomas.
May I have a word with you?
We're gonna handle
the interview from here.
- Have any of you spoken to her yet?
- Not yet.
- This is everything we have on her.
- We're good. We're good.
Thank you, gentlemen.
We will take it from here.
Assalam-alaikum.
You disrespect the Prophet?
Walaikum-assalam.
Katherine,
are there more bombs?
My name is Veronica.
I was born in a tent
with three walls
that said UNICEF on the sides
to a mother who could not
write her own name.
You were born in a room
full of flowers and balloons.
Your mother is a nurse.
She calls you Katie.
- You know nothing about me.
- Your best friend, Gina Crawford,
works at a Starbucks in Cambridge
where you tried
to convert her to Islam
- between skinny caramel macchiatos.
- You know nothing.
Are there more bombs?
More bombers?
You sent Gina a text
right after the bombing
that said,
"A lot more people are killed
every day in Syria
and other places.
Innocent people."
Did you see the footage
on television?
We found explosive residue
from the bombs in your apartment.
On your kitchen table.
In your kitchen sink.
The kitchen where you made
breakfast for your daughter.
Are there more bombs?
You met Tamerlan in a bar
your sophomore year
- at Suffolk University.
- I want a lawyer.
Tell me, Katie,
what are the rewards
for the wife of a mujahid?
If one's husband
becomes shahid,
what are the gifts
bestowed upon his wife?
Your mind is too small
to understand any of this.
- Are there more bombs?
- I want a lawyer.
- No.
- No?
- No, what?
- No.
- I have rights.
- You ain't got shit, sweetheart.
- Are there more bombs?
- Am I under arrest?
- No? Then you can't keep me.
Sit!
Who the fuck are these guys?
Are there more bombs?
You're crazy!
You're bat-shit crazy, you know that?
You are out of your mind.
Your fucking mind.
Katie...
your husband is gone.
Forever.
Sweetheart,
you are now a widow.
And have deserted your daughter,
who will grow up knowing
her father was a monster.
Stop. Stop!
He didn't even kiss you
before he left...
did he?
Katie, for the sake
of your daughter...
are there any more bombs?
For a Muslim woman,
marriage is a lilting dance
of duality...
strength and submission.
Beautiful, selfless,
rapturous love of two masters,
the carnal and the divine.
The life a Muslim woman lives
is a dangerous
and difficult one.
If she does not
submit to her husband,
there is a spot reserved
for her in Hell.
Yes.
My husband kissed me
before he left,
and he will kiss me again
when I see him in Heaven.
And you can't prove anything.
Excuse me.
- What do you think?
- I think she knew.
But you're never gonna prove it.
If there are more bombs out there,
she'll never tell us.
How could a mother do that
to her daughter?
Good luck, huh.
Please tell me
you have something for us
because we're losing daylight
and I have some decisions to make.
She's not talking.
Mr. Governor,
we ran a Guardian search.
Black Hat was watchlisted.
He was right there all along,
and we missed him.
All these guys.
All these leads.
You see a Chechen
who's not AI-Qaeda,
- not even Middle Eastern...
- Come on, Rick. Fuck that.
We all had access
to the same database.
I mean, who was lookin' for
some narcissistic little princess?
Some whiny little bitch who threw
a tantrum because he lost a fight.
Everybody found out
he beat up his girlfriend?
He's no martyr.
He's a fucking coward.
We covered Barker Street.
We got Washburn...
You think this shit is preventable?
- "Preventable"?
- Yeah.
Seven years ago...
on March 11th...
went to the doctor.
Said we couldn't have any kids.
Carol couldn't have any babies.
Jesus, Tommy.
I didn't know that.
I remember after,
right after, we went home,
parked the car in the driveway,
and you don't make this kinda stuff up,
right there,
the Mulaney kids.
Three little girls out there
playin' hopscotch.
Little five-year-old girls.
I don't know, we just sat there
dead quiet watchin' 'em play.
- It was like we were in a trance.
- Jesus.
Sound that Carol made,
it wasn't cryin'.
It was deeper.
No, cryin' does not describe
that kinda sound.
I looked into her eyes,
and it wasn't pain.
More like war.
Like a war between good and evil
right there in her eyes.
Like the devil attacked,
and God was inside of her fightin' back.
We got your back.
I just held her.
What could I do? You know?
That's all I saw today.
Good versus evil,
love versus hate.
The devil hits you like that,
there's only one weapon
you have to fight back with.
It's love.
That's the only thing he can't touch.
What are we gonna do?
We hunt 'em down.
Catch them, kill them, all that?
Still gonna get us.
No way it can ever be
entirely preventable.
Wrap our arms around each other.
Let love power us, feed us.
I don't think there's any way
that they could ever win.
I always knew there was
a thing of beauty
buried deep in the holy soul
of Tommy Saunders.
Four days ago,
you and I stood over the body
of a dead kid.
We can't go back to
all those families with nothin'.
We owe 'em better.
Bet I'll run the Marathon before you.
It's "befo' you."
Before you.
"Befo' you."
The "R" is silent.
Befo' you.
Honey, I'm gonna have a smoke.
- Just gonna be right here, okay?
- No, no, come on.
Come on, get your foot in.
Get your foot in.
The roller's outta the hull.
- It's okay.
- Came loose from the cover.
- It's gonna ruin the hull.
- Come on.
It'll just take me
one second, okay?
- I'm just gonna run out and fix it.
- They'll shoot you!
You're not allowed
to be out there!
Sir! I just got a call.
Someone thinks they saw someone
suspicious hide in a boat down the street.
- In a boat?
- A boat.
Hey, Tommy!
- What you got? What's up?
- He's in the boat.
- What?
There's someone in my boat.
There's someone in your boat?
Where's the boat?
My boat's right around back.
It's got little rollers that
go underneath the cover,
- and the rollers came off.
- Go ahead, call it in.
This is Yankee T-3.
We have a possible individual
in a boat at 67 Franklin.
- Hey, you got a basement?
- Yes.
Go in the house, get your family
in the basement, do not move.
Easy, Tommy. Easy.
Fuck! Fuck!
- Jesus.
- What do you got?
- Shut them the fuck up!
- What the fuck?
It's him. He's in there.
He's in the fuckin' boat.
It could be rigged
to fuckin' blow! Let's go!
- We're gonna get him!
- Guys, guys, get back.
- Get back in your vehicles.
- Fuck, fuck, fuck.
Secure the street!
Clear these fuckin' houses!
This is Yankee T-3.
We need an EOD
and a tac team at 67 Franklin.
We got a possible suspect
in the backyard in a boat.
He may have a bomb.
Stand down
and let the tactical unit do their job.
Hey! Hey! You gettin' me?
What frequency are you on?
- Nah, I don't hear ya.
- What?
The whole state's
fuckin' here, Tommy.
And everyone's
on a different frequency.
Guys, radio discipline, please!
Stay off the air.
Hold back, please.
- He's moving!
- Movement!
Hold your fire!
Jesus Christ!
Guys, lower your weapons.
Everyone.
Shit.
I'll tell ya,
that boat ain't gonna float.
If you're just tuning in right now,
there has been what appears to be
a major development in what
has been a 19-hour search
for a 19-year-old
bombing suspect
for the Marathon bombing.
And it has turned into
just absolute mayhem.
It's time to end this.
All state and local units
stand down immediately.
FBI Hostage Rescue
will be taking over.
All right, let's get strikin'.
Victor 1-1, Victor 2-4,
let's move everybody
into position.
We 're clear out here.
- Who the fuck are you?
- Ma'am, we're with the FBI.
You can go ahead and step down now.
We got this.
The FBI? Boston FBI?
No, ma'am.
We're from Quantico.
Well, I'm from Framingham,
Massachusetts,
and this is my spot,
and I ain't fuckin' leaving.
Glad to have you with us, ma'am.
Victor 4-4, Victor 1-1,
I got the boat.
We have the boat.
Baseline green.
We got the boat.
Victor 1-1, Victor 2-8,
run a few rounds
of 40 Mike bang in there,
try to shake this fellow up
a little bit.
Excuse me, ma'am.
This is about to get pretty loud.
I don't give a fuck!
Come on out!
Come on, Dzhokhar!
Let's go!
Okay, we have movement.
We have movement.
Arm's moving.
Victor 3-6. One in custody.
Yeah!
Police took 19-year-old
Dzhokhar Tsarnaev into custody.
Dangerous,
as we saw. They got him alive.
There is a great sense of relief.
This is something.
A crowd celebrating the news of
the arrest of suspect number two
in the Boston Marathon bombing.
Let's go, Boston!
We have to thank, definitely,
the public for the tips
and the help and the information
that we've gotten from them...
Thank you. You're the best
to ever wear that uniform.
All right, Boston!
This jersey that we wear today,
it doesn't say "Red Sox."
It say "Boston."
We wanna thank you,
Mayor Menino...
Governor Patrick...
the whole police department...
for the great job
that they did this past week.
This is our fuckin' city.
And nobody gonna
dictate our freedom.
Stay strong!
Two people took many days
and weeks to plan out hate.
But love responded
in an instant.
The bombs went off
and wreaked incredible havoc,
death, and destruction.
But in that immediate
instant afterward,
people ran toward us.
I first heard the term
"Boston Strong"
about two days
into the investigation.
And for me,
it was emblematic of
how tough the city
and its residents can be.
I'm a true patriot.
I really do believe in America.
And I think Boston Strong,
it just shows that
we're gonna stand up
and defend ourselves.
We're not gonna take it
and be beaten down.
We're not gonna bother you,
but don't come at us because
we're gonna come back at ya.
When's the last time
you saw crowds of people
cheering the police on like that?
That brought tears to my eyes.
It really did.
When we captured him,
it was the best feeling in the world.
As a police officer, I don't ever
remember having a better feeling.
It's almost like
we just won the war.
In the weeks after the bombings,
when I had the opportunity
to visit many of the most
severely injured Boston
Marathon bombing survivors,
I was absolutely amazed
by the strength and resiliency
of the human spirit
exhibited in these individuals.
It was absolutely amazing.
I think that day on Boylston Street,
the bombers took lives and limbs...
they took some of
our sense of security,
but they took a lot less
than they intended.
And they gave us back some
things they didn't intend us.
They gave us a stronger sense
of community, of common cause.
And I think we've seen that
in other examples around the world.
When we see the news
that another attack has happened,
in Brussels, Islamabad, Nice,
Orlando, San Bernardino, Paris...
I think it's important we think about
these people around the world
not as victims of violence,
but ambassadors for peace.
You know, I have a tremendous
amount of optimism
and hope for the future.
Going forward with Leo,
I hope that he views the world
with open eyes,
lots of questions,
and a sense of humor.
This has been the absolute worst
and lowest time in our lives,
as well as the best.
As bizarre as that is to say,
and not that I don't miss my legs,
I miss them every day,
but after being the recipients
of such incredible care
and kindness,
the very least I can do
is get out of bed and try again.
And try to make this world
a little bit better for somebody else.
About two years after the bombing,
I got a running leg
and started to practice with it.
But I still didn't know
I could get to the finish line
until we took the turn
onto Boylston.
That was the hardest stretch
of the race
because it was
running past the spot
where a bomb had gone off
and changed our lives,
took the lives of three others.
And here comes Patrick Downes.
Patrick Downes,
who lost a leg in 2013,
met by his wife,
Jessica Kensky.
There are great moments.
There are inspiring moments.
There are moments
to savor and treasure.
♪ All of my dreams
seem to fall by the side ♪
♪ Like a discarded thought
or the day's fading light ♪
♪ But I know that if I could
just see you tonight ♪
♪ Forever ♪
♪ At times we may fall,
like we all tend to do ♪
♪ But I'll reach out
and find that I've run into you ♪
♪ Your strength is the power
that carried me through ♪
♪ Forever ♪
♪ Your kindness for weakness
I never mistook ♪
♪ I worried you often,
yet you understood ♪
♪ This life is so fleeting,
these troubles won't last ♪
♪ Forever ♪
♪ Inspired me truly,
you did from the start ♪
♪ To not be afraid
and to follow my heart ♪
♪ There's a piece of you with me
they can't tear apart ♪
♪ Forever ♪
♪ At times we may fall ♪
♪ Like we all tend to do ♪
♪ Your strength is the power ♪
♪ That carried me through ♪
♪ Forever ♪
♪ Forever I'll find you,
forever we'll be ♪
♪ Forever your power
and strength stays with me ♪
♪ Forever I'll find you,
forever we'll be ♪
♪ Forever your power
and strength stays with me ♪
♪ Forever ♪